[Music]
gen z's are entering the workforce
millennials are beginning to settle down
all of that is happening in the context
of a pandemic and these are really our
future leaders the future drivers of
social economic change for our country
so we thought it would be really really
interesting to understand and take a
nice good look at how the pandemic has
affected them so our first key finding
is that gen y's and seas have become
more financially conscious because of
the pandemic their top stressor or their
number one worry during this time is
running out of money they're also afraid
that they might fall ill it is a
pandemic after all they are afraid of
their own death or losing a loved one
again related to the pandemic so these
are the top queries and they actually
have driven what are currently the top
priorities number one is staying healthy
and avoiding becoming ill that is
followed by saving money
becoming financially independent
finding work that is well paying
securing a well-paying job and
establishing a business so some of the
changes that we have learned about or
seen the young filipinos are taking
steps to
improve their financial health during
this time and 81 percent of the
population that we serve they told us
they already take necessary steps to
make sure they build a financially
secure future for themselves related i
think to prioritizing needs over once
only 19 actually told us that they still
set aside money for luxuries so while
they spend a little bit more they
actually became financially aware a
little bit earlier so gen z started
saving at 17 started investing at 21.
millennials started saving at 23 and
started investing at 27. so the
awareness and the action around
financial health financial wellness has
started a little bit earlier for this
younger generation and right now
seventy-seven percent of the gen z's
that we spoke with told us that they are
already researching about finance but
because millennials have been earning
longer and are of course um older than
gen z
their financial literacy is a little bit
more established already at this time so
67 of them are already investing 79 are
looking not just to save but also to
grow their money and 77 are minimizing
their investment risks by diversifying
their portfolio the second thing we
found is that one of the top stressors
is declining mental health and what we
actually found is that this is much more
heightened in gen z particularly those
who are still in school some of the
things that are affecting that are what
they describe as toxic social media post
so that causes some anxiety and also it
heightens
their fears and their worries about
their peers getting ahead interestingly
53 percent of them actually told us that
they during the social media to cope
with stress as well now it's a little
different for working gen z and
millennials their concerns are a little
bit more related to financial wellness
millennials have become more focused on
growing their money first their approach
to investment is a little different it's
a little more balanced there's a higher
penetration for all products among
millennials this is probably because
they've been working more they've been
financially independent for longer and
earning longer so the capacity to invest
is larger than gen z at this point but
the interesting thing is as we look at
the top investment types the
distribution begins to sort of even out
especially for the top three so number
one is insurance bonds are second
cryptocurrency is actually gaining
popularity as an investment avenue the
other thing i think that stood out was
both in terms of their priorities and
their reasons for saving these young
filipinos have very entrepreneurial
aspirations and because of that they are
taking a long-term well-balanced
approach to not just saving but also
growing their money to make sure that
they can achieve those goals i think
what we see here is that the pandemic
has really sped up adulting for these
two generations again forcing everyone
to focus more on needs and wants forcing
everyone to take stock of where they are
financially and also health-wise to make
sure that they build the necessary
physical muscle and also financial
muscle to be
stable and to be strong in the long run
and make their everyday better